





#### **OBJECTIVE**

My aim is to continue my growth as a software developer, increase my understanding over anything/everything, and grow personally. More importantly though, use accessible/responsive design to create web experiences for all to enjoy, regardless of what device you use or your abilities and/or disabilities.



## **EDUCATION**

# **BS in Computer Science – Software Engineering | Oregon State - Cascades** 2017 – 2021

• GPA: 3.56



#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Developer | Mazama

2022 - PRESENT

- Full Stack development: Front-end, Back-end, Devops, Architecture, ect
- Creating new features and improvements to a SaaS customer acquisition chat bot
- Using various tech stacks like React, AWS, Python, and Twilio to accomplish tasks
- Gathering requirements from key stakeholders
- Helping Junior developers with any technical help they needed
- Implementing CI/CD across all old systems
- Refactoring legacy code
- Complete over hall of all front-end (React) to a more maintainable and scalable code base
- Onboarding new SaaS clients
- Creating/Maintaining Python/Node REST APIs

# **Volunteer Software Engineer | Guardian Group/Effectual**

2020 - 2021

 Created a site using React/AWS/Tailwind for the non-profit Guardian Group to help community experts report victims of sex trafficking to Guardian Group for review before being handed off to law enforcement

## **Developer Intern | CBT Nuggets**

JUNE 2018 - SEP 2018

- Created a React site to use in the interview process of QA engineers
- Created a React dashboard page to display automated testing statistics

#### Junior Developer | Redhawk Network Security

2019 - 2020

• Maintained a PHP dashboard used to provide network security services to clients

#### Student Worker and Temp Tech II | OSU-Cascades IT Department

#### 2018 - 2021

- Troubleshooted teacher and student technology issues
- Programmed automated office/IT software
- Contacted various companies/institutions for support
- Imaged Macs/PCs
- Odd tasks

# **Programmer | Summit High School Robotics (FRC/FTC)**

#### 2013 - 2017

- Programmed robots in C# and Java
- Lead other students in the development process
- Teach future programmers how to program a robot for FIRST leagues

# SKILLS

- Programming: React, Node, Tailwind,
   JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Python, C, C++
- Data: JSON, MySQL, noSQL
- Utilities: GitHub, Git, GitLab, Continuous Deployment, Command Line
- Serverless Services: AWS, Firebase
- Agile/SCRUM

- Modern Development Techniques like those taught by: Robert Martin (Clean Code), Martin Fowler (Refactoring), and Sandy Metz (99 Bottles of OOP)
- Requirements Gathering Techniques:
   UML, User Stories, Use Cases, TDD

# **REFERENCES**

Tania Mahood | CTO and Director of IT at Deschutes County
Tom Petty | Software Developer at SOLV
Yong Bakos | CS Program Lead at OSU Cascades
Evan Randall | Equipment Specialist at OSU Cascades
Ryan Sullivan | Team Leader/QA Engineer at CBT Nuggets
Kathie Quick | Math Department Head and CS Teacher at Summit High School
Greig Thompson | AP Computer Science Teacher at Summit High School